Interviews are supposed to be difficult if you don't get every or any answer immediately.
That's OK.
That's the normal experience and it is not back.
Listen for the guidance from the interview, the interviewer might take a more active or less active
role in your public problem solving the level of interviewer participation depends on your performance.
The difficulty of the question, what the interviewer is looking for and the interviewers on personality.
When you are given a problem.
Work your way through it using the approach below.
So first approach I need you to understand is listening.
So listen carefully.
You've likely hear this advice before, but I am saying something a bit more than the standard.
Make sure you hear the problem correctly.
Advice.
Yes, you do want to listen to the problem and make sure you hear it correctly.
You do want to ask questions about anything you are unsure about.
But I am saying something more than that.
Listen carefully to the problem and be sure that you have mentally recorded any unique information in
the problem.
For example, suppose a question starts with one of the following lines.
It's reasonable to assume that the information is there for a reason given to arrays that are sorted
find, for example, and et cetera.
You probably need to know that the data is sorted, so the optimal algorithm for the sorted situation
is probably different than the optimal algorithm for unsorted situation.
OK, so it's unlikely.
That your interviewer would give you this information if it didn't affect the algorithm?
OK, your first algorithm does not need to use the information, but if you find yourself stuck or you
are still working to develop something more optimal, ask yourself if you have used all information
in that problem, so be patient and listen carefully.
The second advice and the flow problem solving flow chart chart is drew an example.
An example can dynamically improve your ability to solve an interview question.
And yet so many candidates just tried to solve the questions in their hats.
When you hear a question, get out of your chair, go to the whiteboard and draw an example.
OK, so we have solved a bit, and we solved the exercises in the previous section about the big go
in rotation by drawing and taking an example of every algorithm in order to know the big own notation.
And later on in the arrays and the data structure and the algorithms we are going to draw also and an
an example on every thing in order to get the desired that pattern in order to get to know that algorithm.
And in order to get what he needs to and what is the sequence that program is following?
The third step in a problem solving flow chart is brute force.
Once you have an example done state a brute force, it's OK and expect that your initial algorithm won't
be very optimal.
Some candidates don't state the brute force because they think it is both obvious and terrible.
But there's the thing even if it is obvious for you, it's not necessarily obvious for all candidates.
You don't want your interviewer to think that you are stuck, struggling to see even the easy solution.
So despite being possibly slow, a brute force algorithm is valuable to discuss.
It's a starting point for optimization, and it helps you wrap your head around the problem.
The fourth step is optimize once you have a brute force algorithm, you should work on optimizing it.
If you technique that's worthwhile, are look for unused information.
Use a fresh example.
Solve it incorrectly and make time versus space tradeoff.
Pre compute information and use a hash table and think about the best convenience store and time.
Walk through the brute force with these ideas in mind and look for that optimization.
Walk through.
And approach after you have nailed down an optimal algorithm, you don't just dive into code.
Take a moment to solidify your understanding of an algorithm.
Whiteboard coding is slow.
Very slow.
So is testing your code and fixing it.
As a result, you need to make sure that you get it as close to perfect in the beginning as possible.
OK, if you don't understand exactly what you are about to write, you will struggle to code that it
will take your longer to finish that code and you are more likely to make major errors.
The sixth step is implement.
Now that you have an optimal algorithm and you know exactly what you are going to write, go ahead and
implement it.
Start coding in the far top left corner of the whiteboard and avoid line creep.
It makes your code looks messy, look messy and can be very confusing when working.
When white boy wants white whitespace sensitive language like white.
Remember that you only have a short amount of code to demonstrate that you are a great developer, so
everything counts.
OK?
Now, the step number seven is the test you would not check in the code, in the code, in the real
life.
Without testing it, and you should not submit code in and in an interview without testing it, there
are smart and not too and not too so smart
ways to test your code, though.
Why?
What are what many candidates do is take their earlier example and test it against their code that might
discover bugs.
But it will take a really long time to do so.
And testing is very slow.
If you really did use a nice big example to develop your algorithm, then it will take you a very long
time to find that little off by one error at the end of that code.
What does this mean?
Instead, trying this approach starts with the conceptual test.
OK.
Hard to spot, identify the hotspot like you have coded long enough to know that things are likely to
cause problem.
Small tests, cases and special cases.
Always try to optimize and solve technique.
OK, so this is the flow chart of the problem solving.